把他們抓出來！
Get them out!
所有泰米爾人出來！
All Tamils get out!
放開我！放開我們！不！我不走！
Leave me! Leave us! No! I won't go!
片名︰悍戰諜影（馬德拉斯咖啡館）
最新新聞
'Breaking news.'
斯里蘭卡總統被暗殺。
'Sri Lankan president has been assassinated.'
使用人體炸彈進行了殺害。
'The killing was carried out using a human bomb.'
根據當地警方透露這次事件發生時，
'According to the local police this incident took place..'
他正走出可倫坡的陸軍總部。
'..when he was coming out of Colombo's Army Headquarters.'
此事的幕後主謀極有可能是LTF。
'It is being alleged that the LTF could be behind this.'
發生了這件事，和平的嘗試可能被延遲。
'After this incident it is possible that peace attempts will get deferred.'
那裡的局勢變得再度緊張。
'And the situation there could get tense again.'
露比，
Ruby,
我想把一切都說出來。
I want to say everything.
真相。
The truth..
我再也背負不起
I cannot carry..
這個重擔了。
...this burden anymore.
你又開始酗酒了。
You've been drinking again.
我告訴過你，
I've told you.
無論你煩惱著什麼，只要說出來，
Whatever is bothering you, share it ...
你就能感到輕鬆。
You will feel lighter.
否則，還是回家吧。
Otherwise, go home.
背叛。
Betrayal..
權利。
Power..
貪婪。
Greed..
我可以在你們的上帝面前談論這種事嗎？
Can I talk about such things before your God?
當然可以。
Yes, You can.
最後一個目擊者，
The last witness..
他還是被殺了。
They killed him as well.
這只是一場遊戲。
It was a game.
一場陰謀。
A conspiracy.
你到底是誰？
Who are you?
你來這已經三年了。
It's been three years since you've been coming here...
你說的陰謀是什麼？
And What's this conspiracy that you are talking of?
我們的總理做錯了什麼？
What wrong did our Prime Minister do?
為什麼我們讓他死掉？
Why did we let him die?
什麼？
What?
我們本可以挽救我們的總理。
We could've saved our prime minister.
你怎麼知道？
How do you know?
我當時就在那，神父。
'I was there, Father.'
那是斯里蘭卡歷史上最黑暗的一頁。
'It was the darkest phase in the history of Sri Lanka.'
最大的道德集團僧伽羅和泰米爾少數民族之間
'The clashes between the largest ethic group Sinhalese..'
的衝突
'..and the minority Tamils..
已經造成了非常嚴重的危機。
...had was going through its worst crisis.'
這場道德暴力奪走了成千上萬的泰米爾族平民的生命。
'This ethic violence claimed thousands of Tamilian civilian lives...'
濫殺..
Abuses..
所有生活必需品，比如食品，
'The supply of basic necessities like food..'
水
'Water..'
一切都停止供應。
'Everything was stopped.'
許多的家庭被毀滅了。
'A lot of families were destroyed.'
因此，許多泰米爾族的年輕人選擇了造反，
'And thus thousands of Tamilian youth turned rebellious..'
他們加入了安南的LTF組織。
'And joined the LTF leader Anna.'
伊拉姆萬歲！
Long Live Eelam
安南拒絕在斯里蘭卡武力面前投降。
'Anna refused to surrender before the Sri Lankan forces.'
並提出了一個獨立的泰米爾國家的要求。
'And raised the demand for a separate Tamil state.'
無盡的殺戮從此開始。
'And thus began, the endless killings.'
這些流血事件讓許多泰米爾人失去了家。
'These bloodbath made many Tamils lose their homes.'
他們到印度尋求避難。
'And they sought refuge in lndia.'
印度政府有點擔心，
'lndian government expressed its concern..
表示不插手他國內政。
...and decided to intervene.'
和平協定是一項很重要的政治決策。
Peace Accord is an important political decision.
我會繼續推進它。
I will be going ahead with it.
我們明天將簽訂和平協議，
We will be signing the Peace Accord tomorrow.
以此來保證在省議會選舉期間，
To make sure that no inhumane activity takes place..
不會再發生任何慘無人道的事件。
...during the Provincial Council Elections..
我已經決定派遣了維和部隊進入斯里蘭卡。
...I've decided to send a peace force to the island.
今天，總理和斯里蘭卡總統
'Prime Minister signed the historical Peace Accord..
簽訂了歷史性的和平協議。
...with the Sri Lankan President today.'
他也宣佈了舉行省議會選舉。
'He also declared the Provincial Council Elections..'
至此，斯里蘭卡恢復了往日的和平。
'So that once again there is peace and normalcy in the island.'
維和部隊的先遣隊
'The first group of the peace force.. '
到達戰地，並向敵方伸出了和平的橄欖枝。
'..reached there with an intention of making the rebels surrender arms.'
想換回這個地方往日的和平。
'In the hope that peace and normalcy returns.'
但是安南拒簽和平協議。
'But Anna rejected the Peace Accord.'
在斯里蘭卡的拘留所，19名LTF成員實施了自殺式爆炸。
'19 LTF cadres committed suicide in Sri Lankan custody.'
安南為此譴責印度
'And Anna blamed lndia..
和斯里蘭卡。
...and Sri Lanka for it.'
他說這樣所謂的“和平”不是泰米爾人想要的。
'He said that this peace accord is not in the favor of the Tamils.'
他擔心如果他們投降了，
'He feared that if they surrendered arms..'
維和部隊一旦撤離，
'..then once the peace force leaves..'
這裡所有的泰米爾人將會被殺死。
'..all the Tamils in the island will be killed.'
所以，他不準備談判。
'Hence.. 'He was not ready to negotiate.'
這將會是一場長久戰。
This is going to be a long war.
印度軍方啟動了一項計畫來抓捕安南。
'Indian Army launched an operation to capture Anna.'
但是所有派去的士兵都被殺了。
'But our soldiers got killed . '
由於安南對於我們的
' since Anna was already in the know of..
作戰計畫和細節瞭若指掌，
...our operational details and intels '
從此，在安南與維和部隊之間
'And from here on, began a gruesome guerilla war..'
展開了一場惡戰。
'..between Anna and the peace force.'
我們的士兵被殺。
Our soldiers are getting killed.
作戰計畫被洩露。
Operation details are getting leaked.
指揮官，我希望你能知道你們的人到底在幹什麼。
RD, I hope you are aware of what your boys are up to.
我們警告過你，不要派遣部隊去。
But we had warned you, not to send the forces.
可是你們的將軍保證我們的總理
But it was your General who assured the PM..
將會在72小時內解除他們的武裝。
.that we'll disarm them in 72 hours.
結果，一年過去了。
And here we are, after one year.
如果情況這樣繼續下去，我們肯定會很難堪。
If this continues, we're sure to get embarrassed.
總理需要給人民一個交代。
PM needs is answerable to the people.
秘書長凱西南先生，我們不是在跟一支傳統軍隊作戰。
Mr. Cahinet Secretary, we are not fighting with a traditional army.
這是一支紮根於當地的遊擊武裝。
This is a locally entrenched guerilla force.
我們根本分不清誰是好戰分子，誰是平民百姓。
We just can't make out who's a militant and who's a civilian!
我們甚至沒有準確的地圖！
We don't even have proper maps!
但肯定的是，如果他們攻擊我們，我們將報復
But yes, if they attack us, we will retaliate.
這不應該成為另一個越南。
This shouldn't become another Vietnam for us.
我們如何更可為難總理？
How much more can we embarrass the PM?
指揮官？
RD?
事實上，
The fact is,
安南不再信任我們了。
Anna doesn't trust us anymore.
並且如果我們進一步鬆懈，
And Perhaps we ourselves are responsihle for creating this situation
我們可能就要對造成現在這樣的情形負責。
if we loosen the grip any further..
這是一個西方國家深入這個島國的絕佳機會。
...It will he a golden opportunity for the west to get inside the island.
而且它已經發生了。
And this is already happening
顧如奇和莫爾蒂忽然去新加坡
Guruji all of a sudden going to Singapore..
度假散心。
...with Murthy for a spiritual tour..
這難道是巧合？
Is it a coincidence?
那麼，莫爾蒂先生，
So, Mr. Murthy,
你想成為最大的民主國家的領袖嗎?
..you wish to be the lord of the largest democracy?
我一直都在說，
I've always been saying..
那是個推翻政府的陰謀。
...that there's a conspiracy to overthrow the government.
現在有一件事是清楚的。
Cne thing is clear now.
只是軍事行動是不夠。
Cnly military action won't suftice.
一切都清清楚楚說明了這個。
All these are clear cut signs.
軍事行動是不夠的。
Cvert operations won't be enough now.
指揮官，啟動所有秘密行動。
RD, get all the covert ops ready.
不惜任何代價，和平協議必須達成。
This Peace Accord needs to succeed, at any cost.
散會。祝大家好運。
That's all. Good luck.
指揮官
RD..
留下來。
Stay.
討論得已經夠多了。
Enough of these discussions.
媒體問了很多問題。
Media is asking a lot of questions.
你必須去干預。
You'll have to intervene.
我已準備好
I'm ready..
動用所有的方式去處理。
...to use all the intelligence at my disposal.
但是我們正在面對的到底是誰？
ut who are we really fighting?
你也要知道。
You, too, need to understand.
現在戰況很緊張。
The situation is very sensitive.
安南不會投降。
Anna won't surrender arms.
他很固執。
He is adamant.
而且其他人都排著隊想要贏得他的信任。
And others are waiting to jump in to win his trust.
我們將會失去這個島嶼。
We will lose the island.
這將嚴重威脅到我們的國家。
And that will be a serious national threat for us.
現在不是去引誘他們的時候。
Now is not the time to go by the hook.
現在是要去問
The time to question..
什麼是合法，什麼是不合法的時候。
...what is legitimate and what is not, is over.
你也很清楚我們要怎麼對付安南。
You know very well what needs to be done with Anna.
派你最強的士兵去。
Send in your best men.
在排燈節前，我們要在那建立一個省議會。
We need to form a Provincial Council there, before Diwali.
斯瓦魯浦，幫我找維克拉姆上校。
Swarup, get me Major Vikram.
我要他24小時內趕到德里。
want him in Delhi in the next 24 hours.
非常緊急。
Urgent.
露比，我要走了。
Ruby, I need to go.
否則，後果你知道的。
Otherwise, you know.. Look,
聽著，我知道我是個軍嫂。
I know, I am an army wife.
並且我必須高昂我的頭和其它的一切。
And I need to hold my head high and all that.
我會的。
And I will.
但是已經四年。
But it's been four years.
我一直都在想你。
And I just keep missing you.
我怎麼可能正常得了？
How do I stay normal?
不要擔心。
Don't worry.
一切馬上就會回歸正常了。
Everything will be normal soon.
對了，不要去看新聞。
Ch yes, and avoid all these news.
自己保重。
And take care of yourself.
如果你真的擔心我，那就不要走啊。
If you are so concerned about me then don't go.
最多過六個月
Six months, at least..
我要想現在這樣抱著你。
Till I hold you again, like this.
現在什麼情況？
So, what's happening?
巴拉已經通知我們
Bala has been informed.
賈夫納安全屋已經啟動。
Jaffna safe house has been activated.
維克拉姆
Vikram..
還像以前那麼拼命嗎？
Still as restless as ever?
這個習慣改不了，長官。
Cld hahits die hard, sir.
放輕鬆。
Relax.
斯瓦魯普
Swarup.
新來的指揮官
Additional director.
我當然記得，長官。
Cf course, I remember, sir.
我在米左拉姆邦行動中見過您。
I had met you hriefly during the Mizoram operation.
好記性。
Good memory.
過獎，長官。
Sir.
我們還是來談工作吧。
Anyway, talking about work..
你知道印度和斯里蘭卡的情況嗎？
Do you know anything about lndo-Lankan situation?
我已經做好了功課，長官。
I've done my homework, sir.
你根本一無所知。
You know nothing.
你將全權負責在賈夫納交火區的所有軍事行動。
You'll be solely responsihle for all covert operations of RAW in Jaffna.
遵命。
Sir.
總理很關注那裡的情況。
PM is concerned about the situation there.
他的計畫是成功舉行省議會選舉。
His clear agenda is to execute Provincial Elections successfully
那裡小的武裝團體已經投降了。
The Small militant groups there have surrendered.
但是那裡最強大的，最殘忍的一個組織，LTF.
The most powerful group, the most ferocious one, LTF..
還在負隅頑抗。
Is still resistant.
我們有對策嗎，長官？
Do we have a strategy, sir?
第一步：摧毀LTF。
one: Break LTF.
目標人物：馬勒亞
The most likely candidate for that: Mallaya.
他是安南的得力助手。
He's Anna's Man Friday.
非常忠誠。
Very loyal.
很難接近。
Impossible to reach.
第二步：拿下Shri
Step Two: Shri.
他是島內唯一一個反對安南的人。
He's the only man in the island who can stand against Anna.
讓他加入我們這邊。
Get him on our side.
還有，你要向馬德拉斯辦公室的負責人巴拉報告相關的官方事務。
For official matters you'll report to the Madras Desk Head, Bala.
他很厲害，並且對於賈夫納一帶瞭若指掌。
He's tough hut knows a lot about Jaffna.
但是，你必須私下想我彙報所有的事情。
But you'll report to me personally, about everything.
有事隨時告訴我。是，長官。
Keep me in the loop. Yes, sir.
還有問題嗎？ 沒有，長官。
Any questions? No, sir.
歡迎登船。
Welcome aboard.
過來，Swaroop。
Come, Swaroop.
賈夫納？
Jaffna?
那裡不會有內戰吧？
But isn't a civil war going on there, Vi?
別擔心。
Don't worry.
我留下一個連絡人 Swarup
I'm leaving behind a contact Swarup's.
萬一有情況就叫他。
Call him in case of any emergency.
印度總理今天已經明確……
'Indian Prime Minister today has categorically..
……聲明那裡的維和部隊……
...stated that the peace forces..'
……將不會被撤回，直到選舉成功舉行。
'..will not be withdrawn until the elections are successfully held.'
而且印度政府不會允許任何外國勢力……
'And that lndia won't allow any foreign powers..
干涉他們的內政。
...to interfere in her regional matters.'
嗨
Hi.
Vikram。
Vikram.
Jaya。
Jaya.
求你見見我
Pleasure meeting you.
這是你的正常狀態嗎？
Is this Your normal route?
我在寫一篇關於難民的文章
I'm writing a piece on the refugees.
你？
You?
小把戲
Chibber route.
你還在倫敦嗎？
Do you still operate out of London?
不是，只在這兒待一段時間。
No, here for some time now.
我讀過你的文章。
I've read your articles.
你就像個憤青
You are quite critical.
批判我們國家的政策……
Criticizing our national policies..
……並沒有讓我變得反政府。
...doesn't make me anti national.
一點也沒有。
Not at all.
那是你們記者與生俱來的權利。。
It's the hirth right of all you journalists.
任何你的文章，它都將成為一本暢銷書。
Whatever you print, it becomes a bestseller.
你覺得你更愛國？
You think you're more patriotic?
當然了。
Cf course.
那些有護照的，和正在申請護照的人。
Those with passports, proceed to the passport division.
那些沒有護照的人，請在軍營裡登記。
Those without passport, please register at the army camp.
夥計，呆在後面。
'Men, stay at the back.'
不管誰之間的衝突…
'No matter between whom the conflict is..'
不管是什麼原因……
'No matter what the reason is..'
首先受傷的總是無辜平民
'The first casualties are always the innocent civilians.'
而且這一切也在斯里蘭卡發生過
'And This was happening in Sri Lanka as well.'
破壞無處不在
'There was devastation everywhere.'
我有被授權的簽證。對不起，夫人。
I've an authorized visa. Sorry, ma'am.
他們允許我通過。對不起。
I'm allowed to pass through. I'm sorry.
你在說什麼？我在這裡。我是一個記者。
What are you saying? I'm here. I'm a journalist.
對不起，夫人。
Sorry, ma'am.
你什麼意思？我必須弄明白。
What do you mean? I have to get through.
歡迎來到佛教聖地，先生。
Welcome to the land of Buddha, sir.
KT. Kamal Tyagi
KT. Kamal Tyagi.
賈夫納安全屋離這裡有118公里。
Jaffna safe house is 118kms away.
護照？身份證？
Passport? lD?
人類是怎麼從所有這些災難中倖存下來的？
'How could humanity ever survive in all of this?'
在這個小島上
'In this small island..'
文明逝去。
'Civilization was dying.'
先生，走這邊。
This way sir.
這是我們的安全屋。
This is our safe house.
通知高層委員會。是。
Inform the high commission. Yes.
我是Sushil Pandey. SP。
Myself Sushil Pandey. SP.
你好，SP。
Hi, SP.
截取的情報？是的，長官。
Intercepts? Yes, sir.
提前過去兩天的報告和截取的情報。
Call records for the past two days and intercepts.
長官。大家好，夥計們。
Sir. Hello, boys.
長官！長官，維克拉姆少校報告。
Sir! Sir, Major Vikram reporting.
我聽說過你。
I've heard about you.
試試這個。
Try this.
當地的酒。長官。
A local drink. Sir.
LTF。
LTF.
最敬業的，有紀律。
Most dedicated and disciplined.
他們在叢林深處運作，從掩體……
They operate from deep within the jungle, from bunkers..
……地下40英尺。
...40 feet underground.
漢斯，這張地圖。
Hence, this map.
記住它。
Memorize it.
放鬆。
Relax.
我們將要在這個階段運行兩個秘密行動。
We'll be running our phase two covert operations.
我們需要降低LTF的最高級別。
We need to weaken LTF's top leaders.
生或者死。
Dead or alive.
LFT。全名「泰米爾人解放陣線」，也被稱為猛虎
LFT. Liberations of Tamils Front, also known as Tigers.
最高長官：Pandyan, lntel首席。
The top leader: Pandyan, lntel chief.
Mallaya，副領袖和軍隊指揮官。
Mallaya, deputy leader and army commander.
Rajsekharan，他們的發言人，一位軍火商。
Rajsekharan, their spokesperson, an arms dealer.
但是我們的英雄，安南 Baskaran。
But our hero, Anna Baskaran.
他根本不需要介紹。
He doesn't need an intro.
另一方面，TPA。
Cn the other hand, TPA.
首長，Shri。
Chief, Shri.
很久以前，他是安南的搭檔。
Once upon a time he was Anna's partner.
他很溫和，想要從政。
He's soft. Wants to get into politics.
總理想要安南屈服於武力……
Prime Minister wants that Anna should surrender arms..
……在Diwali之前去參加選舉。
...and join the elections before Diwali.
讓Shri變得有權勢。
Make Shri powerful.
讓他們窩裡鬥。
Make them fight each other.
這些都是我們自己做的嗎？
Do we this all by ourselves?
顯然是。
Chviously.
我們已經不在部隊了。
You are not in the army anymore.
你們是R和AW之間的仲介。
You are an agent of R&AW.
漢斯用腦多餘用蠻力。
Hence use less hrawn and more hrains.
你會向我彙報所有事情。
You'll report everything to me.
我會通過自己的辦法找出來我到底需要什麼。
I'll find out what I need to through my own means.
我不能再犯錯誤了。
I cannot aftord mistakes.
長官。
Sir.
而且最重要的是，你是一個團隊領導。
And most importantly, you are a team leader.
所以不要被抓到。永遠不要被抓到。
So don't get caught. Never get caught.
接下來幾天，我的主要任務……
'My primary task for the next few days..'
向左轉。
Turn left.
……是找到Shree。
'..Was to find Shree.'
我們標注了幾條重要的線路。
We identified a few important links.
Narayanan同意見我們的時候我們有了突破。
'We got a hreakthrough when Narayanan agreed to meet us.'
你好，長官。
Hello, sir.
我連接到Narayanan。
I got through Narayanan.
他已經同意見面。
He's agreed to meet.
明天上午7點。
Tomorrow, 7:00am.
距離安全屋7千米處。
7kms from safe house.
長官，那個穿著白色襯衫的人。
Sir, the one in white shirt.
這個籃子。它有多重？30公斤。
This hasket. How much does it weigh? 30 kgs.
這是做什麼的？當地市場……
And This is for? Local market..
地球的70%都是水。
70% of the earth is covered with water.
捕魚不是什麼難事。
It's not so difticult to catch fish.
哦，真的嗎？
Ch really?
那確實取決於魚。
That really depends on the fish.
你去越深的地方越能捕到好魚。
The deeper you go the better fish you catch.
告訴我，你想要哪條？
Tell me, which one do you want?
我老闆喜歡你為他們抓到的魚。
My bosses love the fish you catch for them.
你想要哪一條？
Which one do you want?
我告訴你這條屬於當地市場……
I told you this one belongs to the local market..
告訴我你想要哪條？CIA, KGB, Tigers.
Tell me which one do you want? CIA, KGB, Tigers.
他們對我來說都一樣。
They're All the same for me.
我沒有時間可浪費。
I don't have time to waste.
不要想著談判。
Don't even try to negotiate.
Shri。
Shri
你是特工？
You an agent?
戰爭設區裡面，人人都是一樣的。
Everyone is the same in a war zone.
也許。
Maybe.
但是對我而言，沒有滿足感意味著沒有魚。
But for me, no satisfaction means no fish.
你看到了，這個資訊買賣已經變得太冒險……
You see this information business has become too risky...
如果有人要求，我將不得不給處你的資訊。
I'll have to give information about you if anyone enquires.
我需要保存那個。
I need to store that.
現在你可以離開。
Now you may Leave.
停下。
Stop
走。
Go.
你和你的政府會怎樣支持我？
How will you and your government support me?
外面這種情況……
The situation out here..
人們將來怎麼坐在新德里掌控它？
How will people sitting in New Delhi control it?
新德里認識你的TPA.
New Delhi recognizes your TPA.
而我們的總理議程是為完全解決
And our PM's agenda is exactly to settle that.
選舉及和平。
Election and peace.
和平？
Peace?
安南已經把我當成他的對手了。
Anna has made me his archrival.
我們曾經像兄弟一樣。
We were like brothers.
他已經變得對對人民殘忍。
He's being hrutal to our people.
他想要完全掌控賈夫納。
He wants total control over Jaffna.
人民想要看到一個領導者。
People want to see one leader.
說到正點上了。
Come to the point.
長官，
Sir,
我們想讓你指揮LTF。
we want you to counter LTF.
我們需要引入軍隊來制止安南。
We need loads of arms to counter Anna.
引來他們。
Loads of them.
你的老闆們能為我提供武器嗎？
Can your bosses provide me with arms?
他們能保證嗎？
Will they promise?
你能嗎？
Can you?
長官，我們將在這場戰爭中支持你。
Sir, we'll support you in this war.
我們和你同一戰線。
We're with you.
等等，維克拉姆先生。
Wait, Mr. Vikram.
我討厭說謊的人。
I hate liars.
你不會有第二個機會。
You won't get a second chance.
記住。
remember that.
老闆，你需要放鬆。
You need to relax, boss.
Shri不相信我，也不會相信你。
Shri neither trusts me, nor you.
我只是在等待合適的時機。
I'm just waiting for the right time.
他拿到武器之前我們是不會答應任何事的。
He won't agree on anything until he gets the arms.
老闆，請你理解。
Please understand, boss.
你們為誰工作？
Who are you working for?
為Shri？還是為我？
For Shri? Or for me?
長官，我會選擇這條作為我的路。相信我。
Sir, I'll handle this my way. Trust me.
請，長官。
Please, sir.
保持聯絡。
Keep me informed.
下去……下去……
Down.. down..
歡迎，夫人。這邊走。
Welcome, madam. This way.
那麼，
So,
你真的見過總理。
you did meet with the Prime Minister.
他為你提供了你尋找的支援。
He oftered you the support what you were seeking.
但是後來你反悔了。
But then you backed off.
我的士兵交出了他們的武器。
My soldiers surrendered their arms.
他們被殺了。
They were killed.
我逃出生天。
I was backstabbed.
我希望我的人民得到安全。
I want safety for my people.
維和部隊離開之後發生了什麼？
What happens when the peace forces leave?
看，維和部隊多麼井井有條。
Look, it's a clear order for the peace forces..
……保證了選舉的安全進行。
...to ensure that the elections go peacefully.
但你還一意孤行抵制這些選舉
But you're also hell bent on boycotting these elections.
通過和Shri聯合嗎？
By teaming up with Shri?
雙重標準。
double standard.
我已經是一名選舉出來的領導。
I'm already an elected leader.
我有一支合法的部隊。
I've a legitimate army.
立正！
Attention!
那麼這次浴血奮戰就沒有完了嗎？
So this bloodbath, there's no end to it?
我沒有發起它。
I did not start it.
敬禮！
Salute!
那麼如果你不同用政治手段解決……
Then if you don't agree for a political solution..
……你就必須找一個新的搭檔。
...you'll have to find a new partner.
有新的聯盟嗎？
Is there a new alliance?
這是我的領地。
This is my land.
ELAM是我的終極目標。
ELAM is my final destination.
那麼要是我需要從西尋求説明……
For that if I need to seek help from the west..
……那我就會去。
...then I will.
LTF的領導安南曾經一度拒絕……
LTF's leader Anna has once again rejected..
……印度對和平選舉的提供
...lndia's offer for peace elections.
而且早已聲明……
And has further stated that..
……他將不再猶豫去西方尋求幫助。
...he will not hesitate to seek help from the west.
新德里對此如何反應？
How does New Delhi react to this?
著將會對島上的安全進程有什麼影響？
How will this aftect the peace process in the island?
時間會證明一切。
Only time will tell.
Rajsekhara，
Rajsekharan,
你外來的資金和武器。
you source funds and arms from outside.
去見見我們新的外國朋友。
Go and meet our new foreign friend.
我們需要……
We need..
……你們的幫助在我們的戰爭中，
...your help in our fight,
在我們的戰爭中。
in our war.
所以你需要我們的支援？
So you need our support?
我們需要他保證你們在將來對我們的支持。
We need to be assured of your support in the future.
我通過。
I have to pass through.
可以安排伏擊。週邊都被烤焦。
There could be An ambush ma'am. Rounds are being fired inside.
我不能允許你進去。
I can't allow you to go in.
看，我拿到了上校的許可。
Look, I've the colonel's permission.
我沒有接到這樣的命令。-夫人……
I've received no such orders. Ma'am..
我必須過去。隊長。我認識她。
I have to pass through. Captain. I know her.
太好了。謝謝你。
Not had. Thank you.
我看過你的採訪。
I read your interview.
安南怎麼樣？
How's Anna?
嘿，聽著，他不是我的朋友。
Hey, listen, he's not my friend.
但是我會這麼說。
But I will say this.
我從來見過有人目標這麼明確。
I've never met anyone with so much clarity and purpose.
你不能買他。
You can't huy him.
那麼安南一定已經告訴你他的新搭檔了。
Then Anna must've also told you about his new partner.
你在問我？
You're asking me?
直到去年LTF被新德里看上。
Until last year LTF was favored by New Delhi.
但是現在，他們的對手TPA Shri似乎已經代替了他們的位置。
But now, their rival TPA Shri seems to have taken their place.
我不知道你在說什麼。
I don't know what you're talking about.
有些人該出手幫他們了。
Somehody has got to be helping them.
為什麼告訴我？
Why tell me?
這是你的工作，不是嗎？
It's your job, isn't it?
武器簽約的日子定在了七月六號。
"The date for arms deal was decided as 6th July.
武器運到了Shri手上，這很重要。
'It was important that the arms consignment reached Shri.'
你好，隊長 Murli。
Hello. Capt. Murli.
交割在新加坡完成。
Delivery will be made from Singapore.
從這裡。
From here.
通過使用漁船，我們會做出改變。
By using fishing boats, we'll make the exchange.
還有這裡，是降落點。
And this here, is the dropping point.
佩德羅角。
Point Pedro.
四點交收。但是我不知道……
Delivery at 4:00pm. 'But I didn't know that..'
這個小的武器單子將會永遠改變當地政局……
'This small arms deal will change hoth the local politics..'
和我的生活
'..and my life forever.'
禮物在從新加坡到這裡的路上。
Gifts are on the way from Singapore.
保證他們到達我們新朋友的手上。
Be sure they reach our new friends.
別擔心，瑞德。
Don't worry, Reed.
我的人會在哪兒陪著我們的新朋友。
My man will be there with our new friends.
維克拉姆，你將會得到一份從老船中過來的安全協議。
Vikram, you will get a safe passage from the old ship yard.
長官，斯里蘭卡部隊的上尉。Ratnayake 會等著你。
Sri Lankan army's Capt. Ratnayake will be waiting for you.
給他錢
Just pay him the money
登陸將在:佩德羅角。
Landing will happen at: Point Pedro.
印度人在路上。現在離開。
Indians are on their way. Leave now.
好的，出去。
Okay. Over and out.
我們走。我們走。
Let's go. Let's go.
別著急。
Common hurry
我們走。
Let's move.
走走，快。
Move move, Fast
LTF裡的叛徒都在做什麼呢，長官？
What are LTF rebels doing here, sir?
KT，不對勁。我檢查一下。
KT, something is wrong. Let me check.
KT！
KT!
報告位置
Take position
KT！
KT!
SP!SP。KT被襲擊了。
SP! SP, KT is hit!
發送後退！
Send backup!
我們走，我們走。
Lets go, lets go
上來，KT!上來！
Get up, KT! Get up!
立正！
Attention!
安南，這些是火箭筒，
Anna these are rocket launchers,
這些是AK-47 和 AK-56
and these are AK-47 & AK-56
有人嗎？
Hello?
KT的上級，在賈夫納呼叫。
I'm KT's senior calling from Jaffna.
KT他……
KT is..
請，夫人。
Please, ma'am.
我們盡力了。
We did all we could do.
長官。
Sir.
高興了？
Happy?
我們失去了重要人物。
We lost an important man
出去，滾出去！
Out! Get out!
我問過你什麼？
What had I asked you?
如果你自己控制不了她，我可以幫忙。
"If you can't handle it by yourself I can help.."
我是不是說過那些？
Did I or did I not say that?
現在怎麼樣？
What now?
一場比賽聚會？
A marching party?
長官，有人兩次路過我們。
Sir, someone double-crossed us.
不要給我胡扯！
Don't give me that hullshit!
維克拉姆，你知道你有什麼問題，你太自以為聰明了！
Vikram, you know what your prohlem is, you think you're too smart!
長官，相信我，長官。LTF不在那兒。
Sir. Trust me, sir. LTF was not supposed to be there.
我不知道從哪裡開始隨機發射。
I don't know from where the random firing started.
你知道這樣做的結果嗎？
Do you know what be the result of this?
安南和Shri，他倆將會打到我們。
Anna and Shri, hoth of them will hunt us down.
你好？長官……
Hello? Sir..
怎麼了！
What!
RD長官在線上。
RD sir is on the line.
當然，長官。
Sure, sir.
我會接管。
I will take control.
是的。
Yes.
你現在滾出賈夫納。
Now you get out of Jaffna.
直接去Colombo安全屋。
Go straight to the Colombo safe house.
呆在那兒。
And stay there.
德里還沒有選出他的路。
Delhi still hasn't altered its ways.
同樣的舊策略。
The same old strategy.
不是這樣。我們想支持你。
It's not so. We want to support you.
你給了這麼強大的武器托運到LTF。
You gave such a big arms consignment to LTF.
這就是你支援我們的方式！
This is how you'll support us!
有伏擊。
There was an ambush.
我讓一個男人大失所望。
I too lost a man.
另一個人，維克拉姆，他來這裡兌現他的承諾。
The other guy, Vikram, he came here and made big promises.
你知道為什麼他還活著嗎？
Do you know why he is still alive?
我告訴我的人他是你們的人。
I told my men that he's your man.
那是個誤會。
It was a mistake
胡扯，這就是報復安南的方式？
Bullshit, This is how I'll counter Anna?
我私下裡會控制住他。
I'll handle him personally.
24小時。
24 hours.
和他談妥。
Deal with him.
如果你不這麼做，我就會這麼做。
If you don't then I will.
他已經去了隊長那裡。Murli的店。
He's gone to Capt. Murli's shop.
在碼頭發生了什麼事？
What happened at the jetty?
我不知道。
I don't know.
誰通知LTF？
Who informed LTF?
我不知道。我真的不知道。
I don't know. I really don't know.
沒有人知道武器合同。
No one knew about the arms deal.
他們怎麼找出來的？
How did they find out about it?
我不知道，真的，長官。對天發誓。
I don't know, please, sir. For God's sake.
我不知道，長官。
I don't know, sir.
是的，長官。
Right, sir.
讓他活著……別殺他
Keep him alive.. don't kill him
Jaya，告訴我那個記者的房間號。
Jaya, the journalist's room number please.
403.
Jaya。
Jaya.
Jaya，是我。
Jaya, it's me.
我需要和你談談。
I need to talk to you.
安南可能拿到那些武器。
Anna would get tbe arms.
你知道，是吧？
You knew about it, didn't you?
這是政府協議嗎？
Is this an official interrogation, Mr. RAW?
因為如果是這樣，我的答案是否定的。
Because if it is, my answer is no.
你是怎麼知道的？
How did you know?
我需要知道。
I need to know.
什麼意思？
Excuse me?
你為什麼問我這個？
Why are you asking me this?
我有自己的網路。
I have my networks.
那是我的工作。
That's my job.
你應該知道它是怎麼運作的。
You should know how it works.
Jaya，求你了。
Jaya, please.
如果安南想要掌握更多的權力，就會有所反應。
If Anna is being made more powerful There will be repercussions.
整個和平進程就會失敗。
The entire peace process will fail.
將會引發全新的內戰。他媽的。這可不是鬧著玩兒的。
There will be a whole new civil war. Goddamn it. This is not a game.
維克拉姆，看周圍。
Vikram, look around.
和平進程已經失敗了。
The peace process has already failed.
我也不是鬧著玩兒的。
And I'm not playing games either.
我在這裡是因為這裡的人們危如累卵。
I'm here because there human lives are at stake.
Jaya，求你了。
Jaya, please.
你知道些甚麼？
What do you know?
看，在我來這裡之前我接到一個我的線人打來的電話。
Look, before I came here I got a call from my source.
一個外國仲介商的傢伙和一個印度官員會面。
A foreign agency guy met with an lndian official.
而且洩露發生在曼谷
And the leak happened in Bangkok
那個印度官員是來自RAW？
Was that lndian ofticial from RAW?
我不知道。
I don't know.
聽著，要是他來自RAW，你肯定知道。
Look, if he was Raw then you know..
我告訴你吧，
Let me tell you,
他們知道你下一步動向早在你行動中之前。
they know your next move much before you even implement it.
所以你應該知道，那不是我。
So you should know about it, not me.
維克拉姆，
Vikram,
這段對話從來沒有發生過。
this conversation never happened.
東西是不會打電話的，他打回去的。
Assets can't call be called back.
尤其是考慮……
Specially considering..
長官，有些緊急新聞。
Sir, there's some urgent news.
請看一下。
Please have a look at it.
剛從斯里蘭卡發回來的最新消息，一名印度國家……
'Latest news has just come in from Sri Lanka that an lndian national..'
……維克拉姆 Singh已經被LTF武裝分子綁架……
'..Vikram Singh has been abducted by the LTF militants..'
在賈夫納地區。
'..in the Jaffna area.'
趴下，趴下。
Stay down, stay down..
印度高級委員會在科隆布聲明……
'The lndian High Commission in Colombo has stated..'
……他們不知道維克拉姆的下落。
'..they are not aware of the whereabouts of Vikram.'
這次綁架被認為是政治綁架。
This kidnapping is assumed to he a political kidnapping.
這種不穩定的局面將演變成什麼樣？
How unstable will the conditions be?
或者印度高層會……
Or Will the lndian High...
現在給我Bala。
Get me Bala now.
夫人，我們理解你現在的艱難處境。
Ma'am, we understand this is not easy for you.
但是這是一起政治性質的綁架。
But this is a political kidnapping.
我們正在談判。
We are negotiating.
但是我們可以聯繫到印度高層，對吧？
But we can approach the lndian High Commission, right?
他們能派過來軍隊。
They can send in the army.
畢竟軍隊是負責任的，是吧？
After all the army is responsihle, right?
維克拉姆是在執行公務。
Vikram was on official duty.
他是在執行公務。
He was on ofticial posting.
夫人，我們需要瞭解我們是在和誰協商。
Ma'am, we need to understand whom we are dealing with.
一個危險而殘忍的恐怖組織LTF。
A dangerous and hrutal terrorist outfit, LTF.
可能甚至你瞭解他們。
Perhaps even you know about them.
所以你的意思是我應該保持嗯……
So you mean I should keep mum..
……我丈夫命懸一線。是吧？
...and my hushand's life hangs in the hargain. Right?
夫人，我們瞭解你的感受。
Ma'am, we understand your emotions.
但是維克拉姆屬於我們。
But Vikram belongs to us.
我們會盡力帶他安全歸來。
We will try our best and bring him back safely.
你好。Bala,到底發生了什麼事？
Hello. What the hell is happening, Bala?
我不知道，長官。我今早剛從馬德拉斯回來。
I don't know, sir. I just returned to Madras this morning.
我們最好的孩子在你的眼皮子底下被綁架了……
Our best boy gets kidnapped right from under your nose..
你還說你不知道！
And you're say that you don't know!
我明白，長官。
I understand, sir.
不管發生什麼你都脫不了干係。
You are responsihle for whatever happens there.
我已經警告過維克拉姆。
I had warned Vikram.
我告訴他要小心行事。
I told him to be careful.
現在LTF還是生氣了……
And now LTF is angry..
要是LTF有責任感的話，那就和他們談談。
If LTF is responsihle then talk to them.
如果需要就部署軍隊。
Deploy the army if you have to.
盡你所能，我只希望我們的職員能平安歸來。
Do what you have to hut we want our hoy back safely.
長官，我和在科隆布的高層聯繫過。
Sir, I spoke to the High Commission in Colombo.
你知道他們不想談判。
You know they won't negotiate.
好的，長官。我現在就離開。
Fine, sir. I'll leave right away.
我現在就去部隊的基層。
I'll leave for the army base camp right away.
士兵姓名：維克拉姆 Singh
Soldier's name: Vikram Singh.
疑似位置：Pallai鎮。
Suspected location: Pallai town.
賈夫納以東48公里處。
48kms east from Jaffna.
布拉沃1.
Bravo one.
大概50名LTF成員集結在那裡。
Around 50 LTF holding up there.
告訴LTF立刻離開……
Ask LTF to leave right now..
我已經部署軍隊。
I have deployed the army.
目標可見。正北60度
Target visihle. 60 degrees north.
長官，他還活著。
Sir, He's alive.
布拉沃1到大本營。
Bravo one to base camp.
定位那個空車。重複。定位那部空車。
Location is empty. Repeat. Location is empty.
狀態：受傷但是活著。
Status: injured hut alive.
有這個你會感覺好一點兒。
Here have this you'll feel better.
你感覺怎麼樣？
How do you feel?
看著你自己
Look at your self
你的新德里認為能坐在那裡……
Your New Delhi thinks that it can sit there..
……另外遠程掌控一切。
...and manage everything through a remote control.
胡說！
Nonsense!
在田野上，在叢林裡……
In the field, in the jungle..
我控制了這裡。
I'm in control here.
賈夫納是我的領土。
Jaffna is my territory.
你可能根本無法倖免。我救了你。
You wouldn't have survived. I saved you.
然後呢？
What next?
哦，你的工作完成了。
Oh, your work is done.
你的任務已經完成了。
Your assignment's finished.
你的封面是棕色的。
Your cover is brown.
你在雙方陣營的打擊名單上。
You are on the hit-list of both the camps.
你呆在這裡的話只會把機構推向危險。
You'll put the agency in risk if you stay here.
所以，你應該離開。
So, you should leave.
和你老婆過快樂的生活。
Enjoy with your wife.
去度假。
Go on a holiday.
還有一件事，你的記者朋友，她也應該離開了。
And one more thing, your journalist friend she should leave too.
這裡對她也不安全。
It's not safe for her here.
SP這邊。
SP. Here
你來幫我？
Will you help me?
好的，老闆？
Yes, boss?
今後我要Bala行蹤和電話的所有資訊和記錄。
Henceforth I want all the information of Bala's movements and call records.
好的，老闆。
Okay, boss.
你怎麼樣？
How are you?
我很好。
I'm fine.
你的傷呢？
And your injury?
露比。我一直留在身後的那個人。
'Ruby. The one whom I always left back alone.'
她只有這一次機會。
'She just had only this one hope.'
一切都會好起來的。
'That everything will be fine.'
我是一個處於戰爭狀態，但是她很好戰。
'l might have been the one at war, hut she too was fighting a battle.'
為她自己。
'With herself.'
還有她的恐懼。
'With her fears.'
我有一支軍隊陪著我。
'l had the entire army with me.'
但是她所有的就是她的信仰……
But all she had was her belief..'
就是“我會回來”
'That I will come back.'
活著回來。
'Alive.'
你怎麼樣？
How are you?
現在，還活著。
Alive, for now.
這次你差點兒就喪生了。
You wouldn't have survived this time.
LTF是支嚴格的隊伍。
LTF was very rigid.
還有新德里，
And New Delhi,
你對他們很瞭解。
you know them well.
莫名其妙地我們管理了。
Somehow we managed.
但是，長官，我被陷害。
But, sir, I got framed.
兩次。
Twice.
儘管倖免於難。
Somehow survived.
因此，
So,
發生了什麼事？
what went wrong?
你在想什麼？
What do you think?
長官，我在武器協議上沒錯。
Sir, I was not wrong about the arms deal.
我們中間存在洩漏。
There is a leak amongst us.
那你的計畫是什麼？
So what's your plan?
謝謝你，長官。
Thank you, sir.
我要找出來。
That I need to figure out.
但是在這之前，我要抱抱你 Mallaya。
But before that, I'll get you Mallaya.
你是對的。
You were right.
整倒安南，我們需要拉上Mallaya。
To pin down Anna, we need to crack Mallaya.
怎麼樣？
How?
你不能再回到叢林裡了。
You can't go back in the jungle.
他們會殺了你。
They'll kill you.
長官，經你批准
Sir, with your permission,
我們一起幹吧。
let me do it.
取消記錄。
Off the record.
你的意思是沒有假期？
You mean no vacation?
我要Mallaya。
I want Mallaya.
Mallaya是最危險的鯊魚。
Mallaya is the most dangerous shark.
你在玩火。
You're taking a big risk.
你會讓我們兩個都被殺。
You'll get both of us killed.
好吧，我要看看我能做什麼。
Fine, I'll see what I can do.
雙倍錢。
Double money.
Mallaya是安南的第二把手
Mallaya was Anna's second in command
他控制了整個東區
Who controlled the entire east region
在選舉中把他拉到我們這邊
And getting him onto our side for the elections...
意味著把lTF突破到了2
...meant breking the lTF into 2
我想見 Mallaya.
I want to meet Mallaya.
你是誰？
Who are you?
你是那裡人
Where are you from?
我是個記者
I'm a reporter.
你為什麼想見Mallaya?
Why do you want to meet Mallaya?
我在報導戰爭
I'm reporting on the war.
我叫維克拉姆，先生
Myself Vikram, sir.
所以你
So you..
想要採訪我？
...want to interview me?
沒錯
Yes.
我一直在等你
I was waiting for you.
你知道為什麼嗎
You know why?
究竟什麼原因RAW的記者
For what purpose would a RAW's journalist..
冒著生命危險來這呢？
...out his life at risk and come here?
Mallaya先生，我們開門見山吧
Mr. Mallaya, let me get straight to the point.
我的上級想見你
My senior wants to meet you.
在可倫坡
In Colombo.
RD在可倫坡?
RD is coming to Colombo?
你又不是不知道安南會很生氣
You know Anna will be very angry.
他想單獨見你
He wants to meet you, alone.
首先你提到了要破壞LTF
First you spoke about breaking the LTF.
然後你準備用TPA對付他們
Then you prepared TPA against them.
你現在又想讓我們支持LTF了嗎
Now you want us to support the LTF again?
我認為我們應該繼續推進省級議會選舉
I think we should go ahead with the Provincial Council Elections.
任選三個代表
Pick any three representatives.
繼續選舉直到結束
Go ahead with the elections and end this.
任選是什麼意思
"Any" meaning?
選擇那些大家都不知道的人嗎？
The ones no one knows about?
沒人認得出來的那種？
No one recognizes?
如果我們想要和平
If we want peace...
我們需要民心
we need the people with us.
我們都知道人們支持LTF
And we all know that people support LTF.
我們就得和LTF合作
We will have to partner LTF.
我不是指安南
And I don't mean Anna.
我們和LTF合作和安南沒有任何關係
We partner LTF without Anna.
我們可以和他的第二把手Mallaya.合作
We have been able to penetrate to his second in command, Mallaya.
他在LTF有足夠的後臺，他可以憑藉自己的力量立足
He has enough backing of LTF that be can stand on his own.
作為一個領袖 那到底誰是Mallaya呢，RD?
As a leader. Now who the hell is Mallaya, RD?
心急吃不了熱豆腐
Hold on.
如果我們還是能參加選舉那麼
If we can still have the elections then..
我們就可能找到保全面子的辦法
...we might find a face saving exit.
否則，接下來的48小時總理將不得不辭職
Otherwise, in the next 48 hours the PM will have to resign.
先生
Sir.
努力一下
Try.
所以，你代表我去了？
So...You went passed me?
很好
Good
你見過Mallaya了
You met Mallaya.
你怎麼見到的啊
How did you manage that?
我只是按照規矩辦事，先生
I was just following orders, sir.
噢，拜託
Oh, come on!
別給我這種狗屁理由
Don't give me that bullshit.
勾結新德里,這就是你做的破事
Conspiring with New Delhi, that's what you are doing.
我的團隊中有個敗類
There is a leak in my team..
就是你
You.
我們為同一個政府工作
We both are working for the same government.
你不能牽連我
You cannot keep implicating me.
如果你還是堅持這麼做
If you do that again,
我也不是好惹的
I will not hold back.
你知道,在這裡沒有人是無辜的
And you know, no one is innocent here.
嗨，Jaya
Hi, Jaya.
嗨
Hi.
你要走了嗎
So you're leaving?
當然
Obviously.
他們認為我現在為你工作
They think I work for you now.
但是很感謝你救了我
But thanks for saving my life.
聽著，我很抱歉因為我  拜託
Look, I'm sorry that because of me.. Please.
別讓我深陷泥潭了
Don't drag me into this any further.
作為一個戰地記者一視同仁很重要
As a war correspondent it's important that I'd be seen as unbiased.
這會毀掉我代表的一切
It could ruin everything that I stand for.
我只是想讓你知道你在這不安全
I just wanted you to know that you are not safe here.
是的，我知道
Yeah, I know.
這些威脅
These threats.
不管怎樣，別擔心
Anyway, don't worry.
我答應保持反國家的決定
I promise to remain anti-national.
我辦公室電話和我倫敦的私人電話
My oftice numbers and my London's personal number.
維克拉姆，小心
And, Vikram, be care.
你也是
You too.
喝你的茶吧
Please have your tea.
我不喜歡茶
I don't enjoy such things.
我呆在叢林中
I stay in the jungle.
怪不得安南像個暴君一樣
That's why Anna operates like a tyrant?
他的殘忍是眾所周知的
He's openly into brutality.
但是不會持續很久的
But it won't last for long.
不管安南藏身在這座島的任何地方，我們都會找到他
No matter where Anna is hiding in this island, we will find him.
選舉會照常進行
And the elections will be held peacefully.
那然後呢
But what after that?
誰會是新的領袖？你就沒考慮過嗎
Who will be the new leader? Have you ever given that a thought?
走到這步就是個錯誤
It was a mistake coming here.
這個錯誤是你們沉迷於戰爭
The mistake is that you guys are addicted to war.
把氰化物膠囊掛在脖子上的小孩
Hanging cyanide capsules around the neck of small children,
把他們變成武裝分子
making them into turn militants...
是你的戰爭嗎
Is this your war?
你剝奪了他們的未來
You are snatching away their future.
淡米爾人可以給他們自由
The Tamilians can get their rights back..
只能通過政策途徑
...only through a political solution.
你也可以做到，只要你成為他們的領袖
And you can do so, by being their leader.
不是通過戰爭
Not through war.
我們的出價很明確
Our offer is clear.
如果我拒絕呢
And what if I refuse?
你沒得選
You have no option.
好好喝茶吧
Enjoy your tea.
第三步，維克拉姆
Vikram, phase three.
安南收到，先生
Get Anna. Sir.
malayal會給你指出安南的位置
Mallaya will give you Anna's location.
精簡的陸軍特種部隊
Brief the army special forces.
我們想要安南 不惜任何代價
We want Anna at any cost.
對，先生
Right, sir.
任務選擇了安南
Mission Extract Anna.
兩個排
Two platoons.
一個希望埋在東方，另一個希望是北方
One will land in the east and the other in north.
維克拉姆
Vikram..
這是LTF營地的位置
This is the position of the LTF camp.
直徑500米
500 meters in diameter.
整個地區都覆蓋著地雷
The whole region is covered with landmines.
這將是我們的降落據點，博泰湖
This will be our dropping point. Pottai lake.
記住，我們只有8分鐘
remember, we have only eight minutes.
維克拉姆,你在賈夫納的工作是暫時的
Vikram, your job in Jaffna is over for the time being.
你要立即駐紮在喀拉拉邦
Immediately station yourself in Kerala.
等待進一步命令，立即離開
Wait for further orders. Leave now.
他不在這，空的
He's not here.. its empty
鎖定目標
Target locked.
掩護！掩護
Cover up! Cover up!
上啊
Come on!
快，快
Fast...
安南，在南面，坐著
Anna.. southern side.. In the bunker.. this way.
我倖存了下來
'I survived.'
我回到印度
'l came back to lndia.'
我的工作還沒完成
'But my job was still incomplete.'
巴拉，我知道他洩露的
'Bala. I knew he was the leak.'
但我需要具體的證據
But I needed concrete evidence.
怎麼了，維克拉姆
What happened, Vikram?
這些人
Those faces,
這些殺掠
those killings..
這些不合適，露比
Something doesn't seem right, Ruby.
儘管放心
Just let go.
最新消息， LTF的領袖安南已經死了
'As per the latest news received LTF leader Anna is dead.'
安南死亡的消息就像野火一樣蔓延
'The news of Anna's death spread like wild fire.'
整個島都震驚了
'The whole island was in shock.'
“整個世界相信我們。”
'The whole world believed us.'
“而且我們也相信，我們的工作已完成。”
'And we too, believed that our job was done.'
Mallaya萬歲！我們偉大的領袖
Long live Mallaya! Our leader Mallaya.
mallaya宣佈自己是LTF新的領導人
'Mallaya declared himself as the new leader of LTF.'
但...
'But..'
安南永遠活著
'Anna was alive.'
你為啥這樣做
Why did you do this?
沒有人可以背叛我們的ELAM。
No one can betray our ELAM.
而且現在，不可能阻止安南
'And now, it was impossible to stop Anna.'
在斯里蘭卡東北部地區，他無可爭議的成為領袖
'He became the undisputed leader of North-East Sri Lanka.'
而現在更加兇猛
'And now much more ferocious.'
總理今天已經辭職
'Prime Minister has resigned today.'
由於早上的突發事件
'Due to an unexpected development this morning..'
在政治壓力下，他走了這一步
'..he took this step under political pressure.'
因為政治環境的改變
'Because of the change in the political scenario...
...在德里，總理辭職。
...in Delhi, PM resigned.'
一個星期後新政府上臺
'A week after the new government came into power..'
我們的軍隊從斯里蘭卡被召回
'..our army was called back from Lanka.'
這是安南的勝利
'This was a victory for Anna,'
針對世界第四最大的軍事力量
against the world's fourth largest military force.'
從這裡開始的大陰謀
From here on began the grand conspiracy.
最後的暗殺計劃
The final assassination plot.
所以，這就是為什麼我們失去我們的總理？
So, is this the reason why we lost our Prime Minister?
新的選舉是在他宣佈辭職後一年
Fresh elections were announced a year after his resignation.
在競選活動期間
'During the election campaign,'
一次新聞發佈會上
'at a press conference..'
'前總理
..ex-prime minister...'
宣佈他下一個選舉的議程
'..announced his political agenda for the next elections.'
泰米爾人，這一次變成你的重要課題嗎？
Tamil cause be an important issue for you this time as well?
如果我們上臺，除了經濟增長
If we do come into power, apart from economic growth..
泰米爾對我來說是一個重要的課題
...Tamil cause will be an important issue for me.
和平在島上
That there is Peace in the island.
泰米爾人應該得到他們的權利
That the Tamilians should get their rights.
這是我們奮鬥的目標
This is what we will aim for.
和平留在島上
'Peace in the island.'
泰米爾人應該爭取權利
'Tamilians should get their rights.'
這是我們的目標
'This is what we will aim for.'
'我的立場是明確的，我想要一個和平的解決方案
My stand is clear. I want a peaceful political solution.'
在這次演講一個月之後
'A month after this speech,
“我們的馬德拉斯台和東南亞海軍力量......”
'our Madras Desk and South-East Naval force..'
攔截了一些編碼資訊
'..intercepted some coded messages.'
雷德，會議是固定的
Reed, the meeting 的is fixed.
也許從現在開始，盛大的圖謀開始成型了
'And perhaps from here on that the grand conspiracy began took shape.'
Guruji...
我們需要採取行動了，這是最好的時機
We need to act and this is the perfect time.
你安排會議
You fix up the meeting.
你在那等就行了，我會告訴你內容
You just wait there. I'll tell you what. Okay.
講話! a...
Speak! a...
什麼事
What is it?
長官，這些都是最近幾天的攔截
Sir, these are the intercepts of last few days.
我已經從海軍情報裡收集了一些資訊
I've collected some from the Naval intelligence.
先生，因為過去幾天這個無線傳送
Sir, since From the past few days this the wireless chatter..
在倫敦、賈夫納和新加坡似乎增加了，長官
...between London, Jaffna and Singapore has seems to have increased, sir.
好的，這是例行，你可以離開了
Yes, it's okay. It's routine. You may leave.
不，長官，發言者之一是安南的聲音
No, sir. One of the speakers voices is that of Anna's.
聽著，要弄明白什麼是重要，什麼不重要
Look, I'll see look into what's important or what's not, in it.
但這樣的聲音不是似乎很嚴重嗎？
But doesn't this sound seem quite serious?
快離開
Go. Leave.
聽著，你做得很好
Listen, you're doing a good job.
讓我一直在這個回路裡
Keep me in the loop.
好的，先生
Okay, sir.
喂？喂？
Hello? Hello?
維克拉姆的住宅，先生
Vikram's residence, sir.
檔案丟失了
The file is missing.
先生，你看線軸？
Sir, spool..
該死的
Bloody hell..
他們都在Cochin
They are both in Cochin.
把你的人帶到那裡
Send your men there.
喂？
Hello?
喂？露比？
Hello, Ruby?
你在哪裡，維克拉姆？
Where are you, Vikram?
為什麼？這些圖片和文章...
Why? These pictures and articles..
有些不對勁
Something is just not right.
你給誰工作？
Whom do you work for?
聽著，別擔心，我在回家路上。
Listen, don't worry. I'm coming home.
不要為任何人開門
Don't open the door for anyone.
好嗎？
Okay?
露比！
Ruby!
露比..
Ruby..
你給誰工作?
Whom do you work for?
我們在這裡不安全
We aren't safe here.
因為你不在，我們的房子被監控了
In your absence our house is under surveillance in your absence.
我們正在向德里轉移  我被掩護著
We're shifting to Delhi. I'm being shadowed.
相信我，我們必須繼續前進
Trust me, we have to move on.
這不是問題的答案，維克拉姆
That's not the answer, Vikram.
這些圖片，這些謀殺，這些文章，這個外國記者
These pictures, these killings, these articles, the foreign journalist..
這不是軍隊
This is not army.
你殺了老百姓？
You killed civilians?
這些謀殺都是政治殺戮
These killings are political killings.
Jaya,她是一個外國記者
Jaya, she is a foreign journalist.
相信我，這是個計畫。我可以解釋清楚的
Trust me, this is a setup. I can explain this..
你這個混蛋
You jerk.
這些天你都對我撒謊
All these days, you lied to me.
露比,我真的改變了行動
Ruby, I do covert operations.
我監管著不同國家的政治和軍事發展
I monitor political and military developments of difterent countries.
保衛這個國家的安全是我的責任
This country's security is my responsibility.
我們結婚三年了，我知道我應該承擔責任
We have been married for three years. I know there is a responsibility.
但是這有一個約定，我不是一個...
But there is a protocol. But I am not a..
我才不管你的約定呢，就這樣吧！
I don't care about your protocol, alright!
我是你的妻子，該死的！
I'm your wife, damn it!
我有權利知道
I have a right to know.
有關我的事..
What about me..
我該怎麼處理這些事情？
How do I deal with all this?
斯里蘭卡..
Sri Lanka..
你在那裡的生活持續遭受著威脅
Your life was constantly under threat there.
你知道我是怎麼倖存下來的嗎？
Do you have any idea how I survived?
今天我嚇壞了，維克拉姆 親愛的..
And today I got petrified, Vikram. Sweetheart..
讓我一個人靜靜吧
Just leave me alone.
露..
Ru..
露比..
Ruby..
喂？ 老大，SP
Hello? Boss, SP.
我現在在Cochin
I'm in Cochin.
我們需要見一面，很緊急
We should need to meet. It's urgent.
現在嗎？ 抱歉，先生
Right away? Sorry, sir.
我沒有多少時間，等我們見面再談吧
I don't have much time. We'll talk when we meet.
七點 沙灘咖啡館
At seven. Beach cafe.
好吧
Okay.
露比.. 我知道你要離開，走吧。
Ruby.. I know you have to go. Just go.
你好，老闆.
Hello, boss.
馬德拉斯那裡好像出了些亂子了
Something really seems to be out of order in Madras.
許多情報和無線資訊正在被交換
A lot of intercepts and wireless messages are being exchanged.
從賈夫納到倫敦
From Jaffna to London.
馬德拉斯，新加坡
Madras, Singapore.
其中一個是安南的揚聲器聲音
And One of the voices is that of speakers is Anna's.
我已經破解了一些密碼
I've decoded some keywords.
類似於-外國友人，協商，中東
Like Foreign friend. Negotiate. Middle-east.
Bala知道嗎？
Does Bala know?
他知道，我告訴他這些的
Yes, I've shared them with him.
但是他叫我不要登記或是破解這些密碼
But he asked me not to file or decode them.
他的行為把我嚇壞了，老大
And His behavior has really scared me, boss.
我覺得你在這裡也不安全
I feel you are not safe here either.
我下面應該做什麼？
What should I do next?
一直注意安全就行了
Just stay safe.
我會知道我能做什麼的
I'll see what I can do.
露比..
Ruby..
露比! 露比!
Ruby! Ruby!
露比!
Ruby!
為什麼是她？
Why her?
為什麼？
Why?
維克拉姆..
Vikram..
對於你的損失..
I'm sorry.
我很抱歉
Your loss..
我該說什麼呢？
What should I say?
艱難的時光
Tough times.
你知道我的妻子和孩子一直在問我：
You know my wife and my children keep asking me:
“你為什麼要做這件事？”
"Why do you do this?"
“太危險了，你一直處於風險之中”
"There's a lot of danger. Your Life's always at risk."
我該向他們解釋說我們的國家被劫掠者包圍？
How do I explain to them that our country is surrounded by vultures?
我們需要保護它...
We need to protect it...
他們又能瞭解多少呢？
How much will they understand?
這就是為什麼我什麼也沒解釋
That's why I don't say anything.
維克拉姆，你需要振作起來
Vikram, you need to bounce back.
不管怎樣，你在這裡不安全
Anyway, you are not safe here.
我在哪裡都不安全，先生
I'm not safe anywhere, sir.
你不能這麼快就放棄這個體系！
You cannot give up on the system so soon!
體系！
System!
我們徹頭徹尾瞭解的體系！
We Which we know it inside out!
我需要你
I need you.
我們有你的攔截情報
We've got your intercepts.
它們已經被破解了
They are being decoded.
我們知道你對Bala說的話
And what you've said about Bala
我希望你對Bala的判斷是正確的
I hope you are right about Bala.
如果你錯了上帝會保佑，
God forbid if you are wrong,
你將會陷入巨大風險之中
you'll be in great risk.
這是一個很大的指控
It's a big accusation.
我瞭解，先生。我需要把它整理清晰。
I know, sir. I need to sort this out.
如果你不在接下來的24個小時開始監控工作..
If you don't start begin surveillance in the next 24 hours..
...那我就自己來獲取證據
...then I'll get the evidence myself.
那樣的話我就要按照我自己的方式了
And I'll do it my way.
先生
Sir.
我們知道Vasu的位置了
We've got a fix on Vasu's location.
他一直在轉移他的基地
He's constantly shifting his base.
但是他最後一個來電顯示他正通向舊德里
And But his last call was traced to old Delhi.
停下來！停下來！停下來！
Stop! Stop! Stop!
趴下！趴下！趴下！
Get down! Get down! Get down!
Bala招募你為Jammu地區監獄的代理人
Bala recruited you for the agency from the Jammu district jail.
我們系統的資訊洩露了
Information was leaked from our system.
他們知道我們工作的細節了
They knew our operational details.
你知道什麼了？
What do you know?
你會有機會暢所欲言的，Vasu
You'll have to speak up, Vasu.
你知道後果是什麼
You know the consequences.
我剛剛複印了這些檔
I just photocopied the files.
給誰？
For whom?
我不知道
I don't know.
我的任務是把檔案送到機場
My job was to drop them to at the airport.
Bala先生的指令
Bala sir's instructions.
Shree的Shri的軍事交易呢？
And Shree's Shri's arms deal?
我們折損一人
We lost a our man.
你也在那裡
You were there as well.
倒車
Reverse the car
誰通知了LTF？
Who informed the LTF?
你？我告訴過你了
You? I've told you.
我只是遵循指示
I just followed instructions.
那個晚上發生什麼了？
What happened that night?
SP帶來情報的那個晚上發生了什麼，Vasu？
What happened on the night SP brought the intercepts, Vasu?
那是我第一次看到Bala先生驚慌
That was the first time I saw Bala sir getting panicked.
“文件不見了！”
'The file is missing!'
他抓著我的衣領
He held me by my collar.
他非常的緊張
He was very nervous.
為什麼？
Why?
別擔心。這些情報在我這裡
Don't worry. Those intercepts are with me.'
你的部門正在轉移..
Your department is moving along..
他的一些情報被偷了
A few of his intercepts were stolen.
他懷疑是SP幹的
He doubted suspected SP.
所以他叫我跟蹤SP
So he asked me to tail SP.
然後呢？
And?
他接到來自新加坡的一通電話
He got a call from Singapore.
誰的電話？ 姓Reed的什麼人
From? Some Reed.
你只要確認這些情報不會到別人手上
'You just make sure those intercepts do not reach anyone.'
我從沒見過他
I've never seen him.
他以前常常打電話
He used to call.
“一個外國代理人和一個印度官員見面了”
'A foreign agency guy met with an lndian official.'
Bala知道這些情報講的是什麼嗎？
Did Bala know what did those intercepts contain?
不
No.
這些情報沒有被破譯
Those intercepts weren't decoded.
SP現在在哪？
Where is SP now?
我不知道
I don't know.
誰把你送到德里?
Who sent you to Delhi?
Bala先生讓我..
Bala sir asked me to...
...在你的事故發生以後消失在馬德拉斯安全屋
...disappear from Madras safe house after your incident.
誰給你的指令..
And Who gave the orders...
...讓你來殺我和SP？
...to kill me and SP?
Vasu..
當遵循Bala指示的時候，你曾想過...
While following orders from Bala did you ever realize..
...你終有一天會成為體系的恥辱？
...that you'll be such a disgrace for the system?
真可恥
Such a shame.
喂？對，你想和誰通話？
Hello? Yes, you want to speak to?
Jaya Sahni,謝謝
Jaya Sahni, please.
Jaya Sahni？你從哪裡打來的？ 印度
Jaya Sahni? And you're calling from? lndia.
請等一下
One moment please.
我瞭解，媽媽。別擔心，我很好
I understand, ma. Don't worry. I'm fine.
我會在打給你的
I'll call you back.
從印度打給你
Call from lndia.
喂？ 你好啊，Jaya
Hello? Hi, Jaya.
你好
Hi.
你怎麼樣了？
How are you?
Jaya，我需要你的幫助
Jaya, I need your help.
我告訴過你了，維克拉姆
I told you, Vikram.
我沒能力幫助你
I won't he able to help you.
我不能給你我的資源
I can't give you my sources.
我們所有的intel資料都被洩露了給了..
All our intels have been leaked..
..一個叫Reed的人
To this guy called Reed.
所以說，他是你們的人。是的
So, it was one of your guys. Yes.
他對國家是個威脅
And he is a national threat.
所以你想從我這裡得到什麼？
So what do you want from me?
我需要證據
I need evidence.
這就是為什麼我需要你的資源
That's why, I need your sources.
好吧
Okay.
我會再打給你
I'll call you back.
謝謝，Jaya
Thanks, Jaya.
還有，維克拉姆，對於你的妻子的事，我真的很抱歉
And, Vikram, I'm really, really sorry about your wife.
謝謝
Thank you.
Reed，你的人Bala對於我們是個風險
Reed, you your man Bala is a risk for us.
他的掩護被破壞了，他正在被追蹤
His cover is hlown and he's being tracked.
你希望我失去他？ 是的
You want me to lose him? Yes.
好吧
Right.
維克拉姆，我到曼谷了。
'Okay, Vikram. Reach Bangkok.'
坐車號5892的計程車
'Take Taxi No. 5892.'
司機會把你帶到海產品市場
'He will take you to Happyland fish market.'
找到29號店
'Ask for Shop No. 29.'
我的人會在那裡等你
'My source will meet you there.'
那就是29號店
This way to shop no. 29 That way
你就是維克拉姆？
So you are Vikram?
你需要證據？
And You need evidence?
嗯
Yes.
那你找對了
You are in the right direction.
我的線人說有個磁帶，五點前會拿到。
According to my source there is a tape and we'll get it by five.
你從什麼時候開始跟蹤巴拉的？
Since when have you been tracking Bala?
我退休前後，在馬德拉斯，賈夫納和新加坡之間，
Before and after I retired a lot of activity took place..
發生了大量的活動。
...between Madras, Jaffna and Singapore.
我做了一些監控，也上報了
I did some surveillance. I reported it as well.
但我沒有具體的證據
But I didn't have concrete evidence.
當我知道你也在調查這個案子時
When I found out that you're investigating the case,
我同意見你了
I agreed to meet you.
維克拉姆，你很接近事實了
Vikram, you are very close to reality.
Reed是誰？ 我不知道
Who is Reed? I don't know.
可能是任何人
It could be anyone.
也許是幕後操作者
Maybe a faceless handler.
除了有這個，
Apart from there this...
很多其他活動也已提升引起懷疑
...a lot of other activities took place that too raise arouse suspicion.
看
Look at this.
拉吉斯哈蘭在馬德里斯咖啡館
Rajsekharan at Madras Cafe!
是的，他們在新加坡碰頭了
Yes. The meeting took place in Singapore.
他們在那裡見了兩次
Two meetings took place there.
第二次見面時，拉吉斯哈蘭被引薦了
In the second meeting Rajsekharan was introduced.
她代表安南
He was representing Anna.
你需要我們的支援嗎？
'So you need our support?'
那意味著，那次會議的決定
it means that developments of...
改變了整個局面
...that meeting changed the whole politics.
嗯，你還記得那次軍火交易的日期嗎？
Yes. Do you remember the date of arms deal?
七月六號，我在現場
6th July. I was there.
這次會議召開於七月二日
This meeting took place on the 2nd July.
正好是軍火交易的四天前
Exactly four days before the arms deal.
新加坡那邊的禮物已經上路了
'Gifts are on the way from Singapore.'
確保我們的新朋友可以收到
'Be sure they reach our new friends.'
放心吧Reed，我的人會在那裡
'Don't worry, Reed. My man will be there.'
所以這些要送給Shree的武器，
That's why the arms which were meant to go to Shree..
都給了安南
...and after those instructions, went to Anna.
嗯
Right.
快點！
'Hey hurry up, common..
也許安南有了新搭檔
And perhaps Anna found a new partner.
這些人是誰？
Who are these people?
是一些尋求商機，大軍火合同
Corporations, big countries, big organizations.
經濟控制權的公司，大國，大組織
Who seek They need economic control,
公司，大國，大組織
business deals, large arms contracts..
他們的執行者都是前機構雇員
And Their executors are ex-agency employees.
被稱作經濟殺手
They are called economic hitmen.
他們是誰？在哪碰頭？
Who are these people? Where do they meet?
無人知曉
No one knows.
維克拉姆，你要知道，印度是發展最快的市場
remember, Vikram, lndia is the fastest growing market.
印度就是我們的未來
India is the future.
所以總有人企圖
That's why an attempt there is to...
將周圍的壓力都推向那裡。
...pressure pressurize her from everywhere all corners.
這是一場現代戰爭
This is the modern day warfare.
這就是為什麼亭可馬里碼頭
(斯里蘭卡東北部港口城市，亭可馬里省)
That's why Trincomalee dock.
這蘭卡的海岸線對每個人是那麼有戰略性
This Lankan coastline is so strategic for everyone.
嗯，所以他們才會支持安南
Yes. And that's why they are supporting Anna...
如果安南掌權
...if Anna comes to power...
他們也就通過亭可馬里碼頭
...then they will gain control...
控制整個東南亞了
...over entire South East Asia via Trincomalee Dock
那將會對印度造成威脅
...and that would a national threat for lndia
所以他們不喜歡前總理
That's the reason why ex-PM is not so popular with them.
前總理不想開戰
He doesn't want war.
他想通過和和平方式解決
He wants a peaceful political solution.
所以安南起作用了
And that's why Anna.
安南是個理想主義者
Anna is an idealist.
他會一直戰鬥直到獲得自由
And He'll he will continue the war till he doesn't get freedom.
他們會利用這一點
And they will exploit this.
在這等著，好的
Wait here. Okay.
打包一下
Package please.
你的證據。咱們走
Your evidence. Let's go.
納薩爾！
Nasal. Nasal.
Ilpa. Pal.
Ant.
有什麼情況？
What have we got?
他們可能在計畫暗殺一個國家領導人
They are possibly discussing an assassination of a national leader.
這是攔截的資訊，已經破解了兩個了
Sir, the intercepts. Two of them have been decoded.
你通知他們了嗎？
Have you informed RD?
沒有呢，我在等你
Not yet, sir. I was waiting for you.
巴拉？
Bala?
他們給他下套了
So they trapped him.
美人計
Honeytrap.
情報界的老手法
Oldest trick of the intel world.
我也很奇怪
I, too, doubted Had my doubts about him hut this..
所以他們曝光了巴拉。
So they exposed Bala.
也許巴拉沒有利用價值了
Perhaps Bala had become useless for them.
他們會除掉或者曝光沒用的人
The And they either eliminate or expose the useless.
這社會就這樣
This is how our world works.
希望他沒事
This better be good.
這很嚴重
This is serious, sir.
我們從維克拉姆那裡拿到的情報已經破解了
The intercepts we got from Vikram have been decoded.
你最好看看
You better see it.
那是安南的聲音
Sir, that's Anna's voice.
這段聲音來自他的駐地
It originated from his camp.
這些話
The words, sir.
花環。重要的。領袖。
Garland. important. Leader.
他們要找前總理。
They are going for the ex-prime minister.
幫我儘快聯繫維克拉姆
Get me Vikram. ASAP.
長官，還有其他事
Sir, there's one more thing.
巴拉的監控報告
Bala's surveillance report.
銀行帳戶
Bank accounts.
有巨額來源不明的收入
Income worth thousands of dollars from unknown accounts.
五個假護照。八張去新加坡的機票
Five fake passports. Eight tickets to Singapore.
每個人對真相的理解不同
Everyone perceives the truth difterently.
取決於你的立場
It depends on where you are choose to stand.
記住，根本沒有什麼所謂的會議
remember, my friend. This meeting never happened.
巴拉，你的錄音已經被曝光了，你必須立即離開
Bala, your tape has been released, you must leave now..
長官，我有證據
Sir, I have evidence.
他中了美人計
He was honey-trapped.
他洩露了所有的東西
He compromised everything.
我認為他們遭到了勒索
I believe they blackmailed him.
是的，維克拉姆
Yes, Vikram.
我們也知道他的秘密帳戶
We, too, know about his secret bank accounts..
和假護照以及出行細節
...fake passports and travel details.
他不僅是出賣了我們，他把整個國家都出賣了。
He didn't just sell us out. He sold out the entire country.
現在讓部門去收拾他吧，
Now you let the department handle him.
但是你要立即回來
But you Come back here immediately.
賈夫納和馬德拉斯的線報已經被解密了
The intercepts between Jaffna and Madras have been decoded.
有暗殺前總理的計畫
There's There is a plot to assassinate the ex-PM.
威脅很嚴重，我們必須儘快行動
This is a serious threat and we need to move fast.
你喝太多酒了
You are drinking too much.
你沒事吧？
Are you okay?
去睡覺吧
You Go to sleep.
不用擔心我
Don't worry about me.
巴拉
Bala.
你為什麼要這麼做？
Why did you do this?
為什麼？
Why?
我老婆
And my wife?
她有什麼錯？
What was her fault?
不是她的錯
It wasn't her fault.
那是個誤會
That was a mistake.
你才是目標
You were the target,
但是你卻活下來了
but you survived.
你很走運
You're lucky.
第二個軍火交易
And the second arms deal?
我被綁架
My kidnapping?
都是你在搞鬼吧，巴拉?
You were behind it, Bala?
據我所知，新加坡的兩次會議上
I have information that two meetings took place in Singapore.
拉吉斯哈蘭代表安南出席了
Where Rajsekharan represented Anna.
那明顯是個計畫好的事情
It's obviously a well-designed plan.
這是一本破譯的線報副本
Here's a copy of decoded intercepts for you.
我們時間不多了
We've very little time.
跟你最好的隊伍簡單講一下
Brief your best team.
弄清楚這事兒會在哪裡發生
Find out, where is it this going to take place,
所有參與者？
who all are involved?
人物，方式，東西，時間，地點
Who? How? What? When? Where?
我需要所有的資訊
I need all the information.
長官，維克拉姆
And Vikram.. Sir.
已經不是總理了
He is no longer the prime minister.
他失去權力了
He's out of power.
這不好操作
It won't he so easy to operate.
記住
Keep that in mind.
我們需要鐵證
We need solid evidence.
就這樣吧 各位
Okay, guys.
第一個代碼是ghosh
Ghosh, first code.
在賈夫納和倫敦之間
Between Jaffna and London.
安南正指導拉吉斯哈蘭
Anna is instructing Rajsekharan.
這代碼沒任何意義
It has no meaning.
是不是Gibberish?
Gibberish, right?
但如果我們把這個單詞反過來
But if we reverse these words..
長官，這個是泰米爾語
Tamil words, sir.
意思是
And Their English translation:
牙齒
Tooth.
螞蟻
Ant.
蜥蜴
Lizard.
袋鼠
Kangaroo.
每個單詞的首字母，就是TALK
First letter of each word, TALK, talk.
我們就是這樣解碼的
This is how we decoded all the intercepts and we got..
和海外朋友交談，互利的交易
Talk foreign friend, mutually beneficial deal.
這是從哪兒來的？
From where was this generated?
賈夫納到倫敦。安南和拉吉斯哈蘭
Jaffna to London. Anna and Rajsekharan.
第二個代碼，快點。好的
Second code, quick. Right.
不要離開家
Don't leave home.
我們需要給一個重要的王子獻花
We need to garland an important prince.
在這兒，家表示馬德拉斯
Here, home means Madras.
重要的王子，我們的認為是前總理
And important prince, what we guess, is our ex-prime minister.
從賈夫納到馬德拉斯
From Jaffna to Madras.
在賈夫納，我們聽到安南和潘迪安
In Jaffna we can hear Anna and Pandyan.
在馬德拉斯，他們打了一個很重要的電話
In Madras The call was made to a PCO in Madras.
我們還無法確定是誰接的電話
We still haven't been able to track the receiver.
但我們正在追查
But we're on it.
在賈夫納啟動薩巴
Activate Saha in Jaffna.
萊西，你負責南部。好的，長官
Rishi, you take charge of the South. Right, sir.
長官，薩巴
Saha here, sir.
我發現了一個重要資訊
I've found an important link.
你對這個有把握？他會提供資訊嗎？
You sure about the link? Will he provide us with information?
如果和上次一樣呢？
What if like last time..
不會的，他已經答應了
No, sir. He's agreed to talk.
好吧，在哪兒？
Okay. Where?
長官，你來一趟賈夫納吧
Sir, you'll have to come to Jaffna.
賈夫納？
Jaffna?
好吧，好好監視他
Okay. Keep him on surveillance
我明天就到
I'll he there by tomorrow.
他的名字是斯爾瓦姆
His name is Selvam...
接著說。他很害怕，長官
Go on. He's scared, sir.
他十五天不出家門了。
He hasn't left his home since 15 days.
LTF在找他
LTF is looking for him.
他曾是殺手集團小組一員
He was a part of the hit squad.
但是他不想死
But he doesn't wish to die.
他說他不想做烈士
He said he doesn't want to he a martyr.
行行好，先生。你答應過我要救我的
Come. Sir. You promised me you will save me
來吧
Come on.
快說，你知道什麼？
Speak up. What do you know?
我不想死
I don't want to die.
先生，我想離開賈夫納
Sir, I want to get out of Jaffna.
先生，你答應過我要救我的
Sir, you promised me you will save me.
聽聽看他說了什麼
Listen to what he is saying
發生了什麼事？你為什麼要逃跑？
What happened? Why did you run away?
他們說我們會襲擊
They said we will attack.
我沒參與過那種行動
I didn't join the movement for that.
然後？
Then?
有些人被選中，進行訓練
People were selected and trained.
有多少？
How many?
來自不同城市的六個不同的小組
Six different teams for different cities.
每個組有五個人
Each team consisted of five people.
他們在哪？
Where are they?
我不知道
I don't know.
他們離開了營地
They Left from the camp.
他們告訴你目標是誰了嗎？
Did they tell you who the target is?
我不知道，先生
I don't know, sir.
先生！ 你在說謊
Sir! You are lying.
他們會殺了我的，你說過你會救我的
They will kill me. You said you would save me.
他說LTF會殺了他
He says LTF will kill him.
先生，救救我，先生
Sir, save me sir..
每個殺人小組有幾個人？
How many people does each hit squad contain?
每組有4或5人，一共6到7組
Each contains 4 or 5 people. 6-7 different teams.
他們一周前離開了賈夫納
They left Jaffna a week back.
去哪了？
Where to?
我們不知道
We don't know.
各個城市
Multiple cities.
但是有一隻隊伍絕對是去Tamil Nadu的
But one team has definitely landed in Tamil Nadu.
好了，先生。今天開始，他已經開始進行南部競選了
Okay, sir. 'He has started south election campaign for South from today.'
而且他說泰米爾將是他的首要任務
'And he said that Tamil cause will be his priority.'
而且他還向人們保證… 是紅色密碼
'And he assured the people that..' it's code red.
發出高度警報
Issue high alert.
讓他們封住海岸線
Ask them to seal the coastline.
通知海軍和海岸護衛
Inform the naval intel and the coastguards.
讓他們攻擊任何可疑的海上活動
Ask them to hit any suspicious activity in the sea.
1號塔的綠光
Green light to tower one
確認地點
Confirm location.
四個節點有敵方嫌疑犯
Four knots enemy suspect
有三艘漁船
Three fishermen boats.
去查一下，完畢
Investigate. Over.
要迅捷
And crack down.
走吧
Let's go.
抓住所有我們知道的LTF成員及其同情者
Capture every known LTF person, sympathizer.
還有那些投降了的人，所有人
Those who have surrendered. Everyone.
把他們每一個狗崽子都抓住
Get on to each damn one of them.
立刻
Now.
今晨，在印度南部各地區
'Today morning, in difterent parts of South lndia..'
讓他們在車上
Get them in the car.
地方員警和國家安全機構
'..The local police and security agencies...
收押了約50名疑似LTF成員
'..took around 50 suspected LTF rebels into custody.'
據稱...
'It's believed that...
此次行動是為了即將到來的競選
...the reason behind this is the forthcoming elections.'
來吧，小子。上車
Come on, backseat. Get in!
先生，你拿到照片了嗎？ 是的
Sir, did you get the photographs? Yes.
他是Kanda, LTF的同情者
He's This is Kanda. LTF's sympathizers.
他是接受安南從賈夫納傳來的第二個代碼的人
He's He is the one who received Anna's second code from Jaffna.
但是他現在處於失蹤狀態
But He's missing as of now.
另一個人呢？
And about the other one?
右邊那一個是Kanankanan
The one in on the right is Kanankanan.
我們在鎮壓過程中抓到他，他在Madurai監獄裡
We caught him during the crackdown. He's in Madurai jail.
我們能從他身上套出點話
We can get some information from him.
你什麼時候來印度的？
When did you come to lndia?
六個月以前
Six months back.
他是Kanda
He's Kanda.
你怎麼認識他的？
How do you know him?
先生，他是LTF在這兒的連絡人
Sir, He's he is LTF's local contact here.
他為難民提供法律援助
He provides legal help to refugees.
護照，配給證
Passport, ration card.
他也幫過我
He gave helped me one too.
從那以後我就在這替他工作
I've been working for him since then.
Kanda現在在哪？
Where is Kanda now?
我不知道，先生。因為我在這坐著牢
I don't know, sir. Since I'm I have been in prison.
你在說謊？ 先生，我沒有
Lying? No, sir.
前段時間，有個LTF高層來過這裡
One of LTF's seniors came here some time ago.
是的，Rajsekharan
Yes, Rajsekharan.
他搭小船來？從賈夫納？
He came by a boat? From Jaffna?
不是的，先生。是我和Kanda，先生。我去機場接的他。
No, sir. I and Kanda sir and I picked him up from the airport.
他從哪兒來的？
Where was he coming from?
倫敦
London.
然後，發生了什麼？
Then what happened?
我會讓你一輩子呆在這……
I'll set you up here for the lifetime make...
讓這兒變成你家，懂了嗎？
...this your permanent residence. Got it?
他來了以後，他們在農場裡談了會
After he came here they had a discussion at the farmhouse.
關於一些暗殺的討論。
A discussion about some assassination.
刺殺誰？
Whose assassination?
我不知道
I don't know.
但是那晚Rajsekharan很生氣
But Rajsekharan was very angry that night.
之後，Kanda先生就讓我離開了
Kanda sir asked me to leave after that.
然後你就知道了前幾天來過的LTF組織
Then you know about the LTF groups that came here a few days ago.
你還知道點什麼？
What do you know about it?
我只是被要求接送難民
I was instructed to pick up the refugees.
我以為他們是普通難民
I thought they are regular refugees.
但是這次Kanda先生親自迎接了他們
But this time Kanda sir personally received them.
你認識他們嗎？
Do you know them?
他們不是難民
They weren't refugees.
他們看上去不一樣
They looked difterent.
他們在哪下車的？
Where did you drop them?
海灘路
Beach road.
33號
House No. 33.
他們現在在哪？
Where are they now?
我不知道
I don't know.
喂，Vikram? 我是Jaya
Hello, Vikram? it's Jaya.
發現Rajsekharan在倫敦
Rajsekharan was traced in London.
他有4、5個不同身份的護照
He holds four to five passports under difterent names.
所以在倫敦，他確實在馬德拉斯咖啡店有個重要見面
So in London, he did have a crucial meeting in Madras cafe.
而且他還有同夥 誰？所有人？
And there were others with him. Who all?
不知道
No idea.
但是我確實為了點別的事打過來的
But I actually called for something else.
真的，真的很重要。你必須知道這事兒。
It's really, really important and you need to know this.
但是我不能在電話裡告訴你
But I can't tell you over the phone.
傳真呢？ 不行
Fax?No.
我要親自見你
I need to see you in person.
我後天就去新德里
I'm coming to New Delhi, day after.
我們後天見
We'll meet day after tomorrow.
Imperial酒店，下午九點見
Hotel imperial, at 9:00pm.
晚安，先生 晚安
Good evening, sir. Good evening.
有幾個人幾天前來過
A few people came here some days ago.
幾個人？ 2到3個
How many? 2-3 people.
他們買了很多工業化學藥劑
They bought a lot of industrial chemicals.
這些是普通人不會買的
Something normal people usually don't buy.
他們來自哪裡？ 我不知道
From where had they come? I don't know.
但是他們絕不是本地人
But they weren't locals.
如果還有消息請及時通知我
Let me know if you find anything else.
好的，先生
Okay, sir.
被驅逐的拉瑪回來了，讓我們慶祝屠妖節吧
Exile Rama coming home, lets Celebrate Deepavali
對不起，先生，這麼晚才說這個
Sorry, sir, for calling this late.
但是，我們被其它無線信號攔截了
But we've intercepted another wireless.
就在賈夫納和馬德拉斯之間
Between Jaffna and Madras.
是什麼？
What is it?
先生，和這個類似
Sir, it goes something like this.
慶祝排燈節 前-總理
Celebrate Diwali Ex-PM..
排燈節…前-總理
Diwali.. Ex-PM..
前-總理
Ex-PM..
有什麼不尋常的嗎？我不知道，先生
Anything unusual? I don't know, sir.
也許他們在重新確認目標
Perhaps they are reconfirming the target.
好的，找出新目標，隨時通知我。好的，先生
Okay. Find out. Keep me informed. Right, sir.
你覺得我們什麼時候能交付？
When do you think we can have the delivery
我的線人會和你保持聯繫的
My contact will get in touch with you
你找到了什麼，Arjun？ 先生，接電話
What did you find, Arjun? Sir, check this.
誰的電話？ 是Vijayan, Vijayan Joseph
Whose call is it? Vijayan. Vijayan Joseph.
你好，先生 怎麼了 Rishi？
Hello, sir. Yes, Rishi?
先生，我們追蹤到了Vijayan的電話
Sir, we've traced Vijayan's call.
在哪？ 有什麼消息？
From where? What's the source?
1號街，Maduria，Mylapore
Street one. Maduria. Mylapore
Mylapore
聯繫德里 好的
Connect to Delhi. Yeah.
聯繫馬德拉斯 好的，先生
Connect Madras. Right, sir.
德里聯繫上了，先生
Delhi connected, sir.
先生，德里聯繫上了
Sir, Delhi connected.
告訴我細節
Give me the details.
先生，聯繫上馬德拉斯了
Sir, Madras connected.
先生，接電話交付
Sir, picking up and delivery.
先生，他們在說交付的事情呢
Sir, they are talking about some delivery.
追蹤到電話在哪了嗎？ 在賈夫納，先生
Call has been traced to? Jaffna, sir.
電話是在賈夫納，先生
Call has been traced to Jaffna, sir.
先生，Vijayan是德國來的幾個人之一
Sir, Vijayan is the one who came from Germany.
他是一個炸彈專家
He's a bomhmaker.
號碼鎖定，先生
number tracked, sir.
好的。我明天就到。好的，先生
Fine. I'll be there by tomorrow. Okay, sir.
那就是Rajsekharan，在倫敦的馬德拉斯咖啡店
That's Rajsekharan, at Madras Cafe, London.
看這個
Look at this.
電話裡你看不到這個
I couldn't share this with you over the phone.
我覺得沒時間了
I don't think there's much time.
四天前，這筆錢被轉入了LTF的帳戶
Four days back, this amount was transferred into the LTF account.
也就是說這是最後的確認了？
This means this is the final confirmation?
對任何一個職業，
For any job,
交了錢都是最終確認了
money is the final confirmation.
你從哪拿到這個的？
Where did you get this from?
我一直在調查這些銀行
I was investigating these banks.
發現，有些銀行都是假的
And realized such banks only exist on paper.
它們只存在幾天，幾個月，然後
They remain for a few days, months and then,
就不見了
they just disappear.
所以，先是前總理的演講
So, first the speech by the ex-PM.
接著Rajsekharan會去倫敦的馬德拉斯的咖啡店
Then Rajsekharan goes to Madras Cafe, London.
估計事情就要在那裡發生了
And that's where possibly things happened.
安南，他要重掌大權了
'Anna, he's coming back to power.'
他不會讓我們做想做的事情的
'He will not let us do what we want.'
他會要求一個政治解決方案
'He'll demand a political solution.'
現在，我們只需要採取行動。
Now we will only have to act
還有人知道你在這嗎？
Does anyone else know that you are here?
沒有
No.
Ahuda 夾克合身嗎？
Ahuda Does the jacket fit well?
但願不是太緊
Hope its not too tight?
不緊，正好
No, its fine
好的。好的
Okay. Okay.
那我們今晚就預演
Then we'll do the rehearsal tonight.
好嘛？ 好的
Okay? Okay.
好的，Jaya
Okay, Jaya.
所以，你要做什麼，維克拉姆？
So, what'll you do now, Vikram?
我不知道
I don't know.
小心行事，維克拉姆
Be careful, Vikram.
前進至3號門
'Please proceed to Gate No. 3.'
十分鐘內進行安全檢查
'security check begins in ten minutes.'
這是最後登機呼籲乘客
'This is the final boarding call for passengers of...
3728次航班即將飛往坎薩斯城
Flight No. 3728 to Kansas City.'
請迅速前往3號登機門
'Please proceed to Gate No. 3 immediately.'
安檢即將開始
'security check will begin in a while.'
不許動 把手舉起來
Hands up! Don't move!
抓住他
Catch him!
不許動 把手舉起來 趴下 趴下
Hands up! Don't move! Stay down; stay down
警官 求你了 別衝動
Sir, please! Relax!
警官 我並沒有參與
Sir, I'm not involved.
去仔細檢查一番 是 警官
Go and check everywhere. Yes, sir.
去外邊看看 過來
Check outside. Come on.
走！ 來吧！
Go! Come on!
你在想什麼
What were you thinking?
你在這裡製造炸藥 你的家人能安全的呆在德國嗎
You'll make bombs here and your family will stay safe in Germany?
這是你的妻子和女兒 對吧
This is your wife and daughter, right?
你想讓她們活著嗎
Do you wish to see them alive?
求你了 警官 別傷害她們
Please, sir, do them no harm.
她們是無辜的
They are innocent.
住在這裡的人怎麼樣了呢
What about the people who live here?
他們呢？
What about them?
你到底向誰提供了炸藥
Whom did you supply the explosives to?
我是被雇傭的
I was hired.
有人告訴我報酬豐厚 警官先生
I was told I'll be paid well, sir.
我不是一個恐怖分子 長官
I'm not a terrorist, sir.
我只是一名化學工程師
I'm a chemical engineer.
我曾在德國工作
I used to work in Germany.
我曾在德國測試炸藥
I tested the explosives in Germany.
三個月前我來到印度
I came to lndia three months ago.
他們向我提供了原材料
They supplied me with the raw materials.
我只負責組裝 就這麼多了 長官
I just assemhled it. That's all, sir.
你組裝了什麼
What did you assemhle?
塑膠性藥
Plastic explosives.
世界首發
First time in the world.
高性能炸藥
High quality explosives.
類似橡膠的物質
Rubber like material.
它的優勢在於金屬探測器對它束手無策
Advantage is that the metal detectives can't detect it.
它可以殺死任何在20-30英尺半徑內的人
And kills it can kill everyone anyone in the radius of 20-30 feet.
他們計畫在哪裡引爆
Where are they taking it?
他們將怎麼使用這種炸藥 無從知曉 長官
How will they use it? I don't know, sir.
任何地點都有可能
It can happen anywhere
德里 孟買 馬德拉斯 任何地方
Delhi, Bomhay, Madras. Anywhere.
他們什麼時候行動
When will they hit?
我不知道 長官
I don't know, sir.
長官 當我們在談話的時候
While we are speaking, sir..
能夠用某種辦法中止引爆嗎？
Can it be deactivated from here? Somehow.
所有炸彈? 不可能
All the bombs? No. Not possible.
但我的家人， 長官...
But my family, sir..
Ghosh 第三情報員？ 女性？
Ghosh, the third intercept? Deepti?
流亡的拉瑪回家慶祝排燈節了
Celebrate Diwali, Exile Rama, coming home.
去弄前總統的集會日程  快！
Get ex-PM's rally schedule. Quick.
給你 長官
Right here, sir.
打擾一下 長官
Excuse me, sir.
航班出現一項技術難題
There's a technical prohlem in the flight.
可能要花些功夫
It'll take a bit longer.
要多久？ 約一小時
How long? about an hour.
好的
Okay.
長官 最後一通情報傳遞於自賈夫納和馬德拉斯之間
Sir, this last intercept is between Jaffna and Madras.
流亡的拉瑪回家慶祝排燈節
Celebrate Diwali, Exile Rama, coming home.
長官 情報已被破譯
Sir, it has been decoded.
流亡代表前任
Exile Ex.
拉瑪代表總理
Rama -PM
前任總理
Ex-PM.
他今日的集會安排
His today's rally schedule.
上午十點 瓦朗加爾
10am. Warrangal.
下午一點三十分 維傑亞瓦達
1 :30pm. Vijaywada.
下午四點 海德拉巴
4:00pm. Hyderabad.
晚上十點 Poothiyaddur
-And 10:00pm Poothiyaddur.
我想說的是 前總理
What I want to say is, ex-PM.
X在羅馬數字中是十
X in roman is ten.
晚上十點
10:00pm.
前總理 晚上十點
Ex-PM. 10:00pm.
Poothiyaddur，晚上十點整
Poothiyaddur, 10:00pm.
你的意思是他們今晚就要引爆炸彈？
You mean they are striking tonight?
我是這麼認為的 長官
I think so, sir.
他現在在哪裡？海德拉巴候機室，長官
-Where is he right now? Hyderabad airport lounge, sir.
噢 天呐！
Oh God!
我們不能冒險
We can't take a chance.
已經遲了
We're already late.
我們必須阻止他 長官
We'll have to stop him. Sir.
幫我接通海德拉巴機場 長官
Get me Hyderabad airport. Sir.
所有情報清楚地表明LTF將目標鎖定在前總理
All our intels are clearing stating that LTF will target the ex-PM.
我們有足夠的證據
We've strong evidence.
首先是倒退開關，然後前置開關
First back switch, then front switch.
首先是倒退開關
First back switch,
然後是前置開關
then front switch.
再來一次
Once more.
聲稱政府反對協議並警告他
State governor went against protocol and warned him.
他不該南行
That he shouldn't tour south.
不，我覺得LTF不會策劃這麼龐大的計畫
No, I don't think LTF will plan something this big. No.
首先是倒退開關
First back switch,
然後是前置開關
then front switch.
我們要不惜一切保護他
We'll have to provide him with full protection, at all cost.
前總理，我們不能向任何人提供NSG
Ex-PM or ex-minister, we cannot provide NSG to anyone.
這違反了規則 我們不能這樣做
It is against the rules! We cannot do it!
如果你固執己見 記住存在威脅...
But if you insist, keeping in mind the threat...
...我們將通知州員警，他們將負責這個案件
...we'll inform the state police. They will look after it.
很好，只要你覺得合適就好
Fine. Whatever you deem fit.
Ghosh 長官
Ghosh.. Sir.
替我開通特殊通道 我要去機場
Get me special access. I'm about to reach the airport.
現在 好的，長官
Now. Okay, sir.
下午好，長官 我是Rohin Dutt
Good afternoon, sir. Rohin Dutt.
我有個請求
I've a request to make, sir.
請您取消今天以及接下來兩三天的會議行程
Kindly cancel your rallies for today and for the next 2-3 days.
對您安全有威脅 您最好避開它
There's a threat. it will be better if you avoid them.
你知道我想和這些選舉者見面的
You know I want to be with the people for these elections.
那裡有安保的
There is security over there.
是的，先生。有安保，但還是很危險
Yes, sir. it's there. But it could he dangerous.
我請求您千萬別去
It's a request. Please don't go there.
先生，對不起
Sir, excuse me.
飛行員剛剛通知了 飛機快起飛了 好的
Pilot just informed. Flight is ready for take oft. Okay.
Rohin 別擔心好嗎 不會有事的
Rohin, please don't worry. I'll be fine. Okay?
他十分鐘後到達 ...
He will be reaching in ten minutes...
請大家自覺接受安檢
Everyone please co-operate for the security check...
請從退到臺階後...
Please move behind from the stage...
要掛花環的女士們請到前排來
Ladies who will be garlanding, please move to the front row
請保持秩序
Please maintain discipline...
...我們的總理馬上就到
...our leader will be reaching in the next minutes
先生 這是我們的行程地圖 Rising已經在那裡了
Sir, here's the route map. Rishi is already there.
好的
Okay.
維克拉姆已經就位 他正在去集會的路上
Vikram has reached. He's on his way to the rally.
所有部門已通知到位
All units informed.
長官， 例行檢查已經結束
Routine scanning is complete, sir.
約有3000到3500人
Around 3000-3500 people.
他馬上就到
He'll be here soon.
繼續監視 我來了 是 長官
Keep checking, I'm coming. Yes, sir.
前總理到了
Ex-PM has reached.
你不能繼續前進
You're not allowed to go ahead!
這是一個沉痛的消息：今晚早些時候
'We're sorry to inform you that earlier tonight..'
印度前總理被暗殺
'..lndia's former Prime Minister was assassinated.'
這場恐怖爆炸事件發生在晚上十點十分
'This dreadful blast took place at 10:10pm.'
他正在印度南部的Poothiyaddur區
'He was in Poothiyaddur district in South lndia,
去參與一場選舉集會
to address an election rally.'
在印度南部，這場突如其來的悲劇
'In the south of lndia, this sudden and tragic death..'
讓整個國家陷入震驚
'..has left the whole nation in a state of shock.'
這是首次自殺性恐怖爆炸事件
'This is the first time a human bomb has been used...'
他的不幸死亡震驚了每一個人
'His unfortunate death has left people in a state of shock.'
舉國上下為之哀悼
'The whole nation is mourning.'
迄今為止 這場爆炸已經奪走了25條生命
'So far this blast has claimed 25 people's lives,
並致使一百多人受傷
and injured more than 100 people.'
一場恐怖爆炸事件發生在晚上十點十分
'A horrific blast took place at 10:10pm.'
這個駭人聽聞的事件在舉國上下引起巨大反響
'This shocking incident has sent shock waves across the entire nation.'
整個國家陷於癱瘓
'Bringing the country to a complete standstill.'
據特別調查小組透露
'The special investigation squad has revealed..'
...塑性炸藥和RDX的使用
'..the use of plastic explosives and RDX.'
這場爆炸迄今奪走25條生命
'So far this blast has claimed 25 people's lives,
傷亡一百多人
and injured more than 100 people.'
他們都是當日參與集會的人
They were those who came to the rally...
...他們支持我們的前總理
...to support our former prime minister.
就是這樣
Just like that.
他犯了什麼錯
What was his fault?
他還這麼年輕
He was so young.
我們努力了
We tried.
但失敗了
But we lost.
總理讓民眾保持冷靜
'President has requested people to stay calm.'
世界各國的領導人發來慰問
'Leaders all across the world have expressed their condolences.'
一段時間過去了 走！走！走！
'After some time..' Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
調查小組已逮捕部分罪犯
'The investigation team arrested a few suspects.'
一些罪犯在被捕前自殺
'And a few suspects committed suicide before they could be arrested.'
我向特別調查小組提交了報告
'And I suhmitted my report to the special investigation team.'
委員會感謝您的調查
This commission appreciates your investigations.
是，我們會參考的
And yes, we will consider them.
但是，維克拉姆先生，我們需要確鑿的證據
But, Mr. Vikram, we need solid evidence.
我從沒意識到...
'I'd never realized that...
..這個世界對我們的總理是這麼危險
...the world is so threatened by our Prime Minister.'
幾天後RD先生辭職了
'RD sir resigned after a few days.'
我希望你三思後再做決定
I hope you've given this decision of yours a thought.
好
Yes.
我自願退休並來到這裡
And I took a voluntary retirement and came here.
您剛剛所說的只是一場巧合
Whatever you just said could also be just a coincidence.
不 神父
No, Father.
這場陰謀就是按照計畫進行的
This conspiracy was played out just as it was planned.
而且 我遲了一步
And I was late.
但我無法與他抗衡
But I couldn't compete with him.
他們太強大了
They were powerful.
在這場博弈中 我們失去了敬愛的總理
And In this game we lost our Prime Minister.
和斯里蘭卡的泰米爾人 他們的未來
And the Lankan Tamils their future.
那麼誰贏了？
Then who won?
不知道
I don't know.
或許每個人都是輸家
Perhaps it was everyone's loss.
安南也是？
And Anna?
一個人的革命是另一個人的恐怖
One man's revolutionary is another man's terrorist.
安南解放了他的人民
Anna is revolutionary for his people.
但我還是失去了總理
But I lost my Prime Minister.
你現在將要幹嘛？
What will you do now?
露比的父親給了我這個...
Ruby's father gave this to me...
...在我們結婚那天
...on our wedding day.
一個結婚禮物
A wedding gift.
精神上無所畏懼 就會高昂頭顱
Where the mind is without fear and the head is held high..
知識自由...
Where knowledge is free..
世界還沒有被狹隘的城牆
Where the world has not been broken up into fragments..
分裂成碎片..
By narrow domestic walls..
話是從真理的深處說出..
Where words come out from the depth of truth..
不懈的努力伸展雙臂走向完美..
Where tireless striving stretches its arms towards perfection..
理智的清泉沒有迷失方向
Where the clear stream of reason has not lost its way..
充斥死亡沉悶的沙漠裡
Into the dreary desert sand of dead habit..
心靈是受你的指引
Where the mind is led forward by thee..
到每一個擴闊思想和行動
Into every-widening thought and action..
進入自由天堂 神父
Into that heaven of freedom, my Father,
讓我的國家覺醒吧
let my country awake..
謝謝
Thank you.